A Guide to the Pocahontas Mines Collection, 1883-1997
Special Collections, Virginia Tech
- Series III. Books, 1914-1995, 64.48 Cubic Feet; 62 boxes (2940 vols.)
  - G and A Coal Co. (CL and levels), vols. 15-17, 1994-1995 (Box B49)
  - Maitland No. 3 Seam, vols. 5, 10, and 11, 1982-1984 (Box B49)
  - McGlothlin (CL and levels), vols. 5-8, 1986-1990 (Box B49)
  - Omega Square, vols. 7-8, 1992-1994 (Box B49)
  - Elevation and Road Survey for Conoco and R.A.O. Coal Company, Bandy, 1984 (Box B49)
  - C.C. No. 6, vol 30, with Ingersoll-Rand Mining Machinery calender, 1983-1985 (Box B49)
  - C.C. No. 12, vol. 1, undated (Box B49)
  - Coaldale Tunnel, 1951-1957 (Box B50)
  - Eureka, Shawnee, Crozier, Peerless, West Virginia Crozer - Elkhorn No. 9 Seam; Eckman-Page, No. 11, 1966-1980 (Box B50)
  - Thomas No. 6 Seam, Dtripping, Deep Mining, 1963-1970 (Box B50)
  - Eckman No. 11 Seam, No. 12 Seam, Pulaski Lease, Echman No. 11-12-13, Eckman No. 9, 11, 12, 13, 1956-1980 (Box B50)
  - Sagamore, Nos. 3 and 11-A-B-C, 1950-1978 (Box B50)
  - Sewall Seam, 1963-1982 (Box B50)
  - Piedmont, 1957-1976 (Box B50)
  - Turkey Gap, 1964-1982 (Box B50)
  - Peerless No. 3 Seam, No. 7 Mine; Maitland No. 4 Seam, 1957-1983 (Box B50)
  - Peerless No. 11 Seam, No. 11 Punch Strip Aug., Crozer Leasehold, 1957-1958 (Box B50)
  - Berwind Mines, New Hall No. 3 Seam, 1961-1973 (Box B50)
  - Buckeye Mine, Stephenson, West Virginia, 1964-1977 (Box B50)
  - Bishop No. 33 Mine, No. 5 Seam, Contract Coal, Horsepen Seam, 1950-1982 (Box B50)
  - No. 6 Seam, Still Run, Fire Creek Seam, 1969-1982 (Box B50)
  - No. 4 Seam, Itmann, 1966-1975 (Box B50)
  - No. 34 Mine, No. 4 Seam and No. 3 Seam, 1950-1970 (Box B50)
  - Ledger, 1956-1983 (Box B50)
  - No. 36 Mine, 1971-1982 (Box B50)
  - Company Owned Strip Jobs, Horsepen, VA; Horsepen, WV; Coalbank, WV; Reed Strip, VA; Monthly Tonnage Reports, 1958-1977 (Box B50)
  - A. Z. Litz, 1964-1978 (Box B50)
  - North Branch (CL & levels), vols. 1, 3-5, 1982-1995 (Box B51)
  - Bear Ridge, vols. 2, 11-13, 1986-1995 (Box B51)
  - McGlothlin (CL & levels), vols. 1-2, 1990-1995 (Box B51)
  - Odd Jobs, 1987-1989 (Box B51)
  - Bishop, 1979, 1995 (Box B51)
  - Pigeon Branch, No. 8, Vol. 8, 1992 (Box B51)
  - Misc-1, 1994 (Box B51)
  - Brenkee, Vol. 243, 1981 (Box B51)
  - C&R #2, Vol. 1, 1982 (Box B51)
  - Brewster Hollow No. 8 Seam, Vol. 1, McGlothlin, 1994 (Box B51)
  - Frontier Mine, Vol. 1, 1982 (Box B51)
  - No. 1 Mine (Greasy Creek, Nichols), Vol. 1, 1982 (Box B51)
  - Itmann, vols. 100-104, 1973-1978 (Box B51)
  - Itmann, vols. 2005-2010, 1974-1976 (Box B51)
  - Itmann outside, vol. 101, 1974 (Box B51)
  - Borehole surveys, vols. 1-2, 1985-1986 (Box B51)
  - Boreholes, vol. 1, 1985 (Box B51)
  - 3 Mine (levels), vol. 29, 1986 (Box B51)
  - 3 Mine (CL), vol. 92 (Box B51)
  - 1 Mine “A”, 1982 (Box B51)
  - Joe’s Branch, vol. 1, 1985 (Box B51)
  - Unidentified, 1975-1976 (Box B51)
  - Odd Jobs, vols. 3-7, 9, 1979-1984 (Box B51)
  - Itmann No. 3 Mine, 1993-1995 (Box B51)
  - Scrapbook, Elmina, 1981-1985 (Box B51)
  - Amonate, No. 31 mine, No. 4-5 seams, 1951 (Box B52)
  - Amonate, vols. 13-14, 1982-1984 (Box B52)
  - Bishop, 1981 (Box B52)
  - Dry Fork, 1981-1982 (Box B52)
  - Arista, 1961-1982 (Box B52)
  - No. 33, No. 34, and No. 36 Mines, 1981-1982 (Box B52)
  - Modoc, 1971-1975 (Box B52)
  - Turkey Gap, 1976-1977 (Box B52)
  - Assorted volumes (19 volumes), including Crozer, Piedmont, Sewell Seam, Deerfield, Rowland, etc., 1945-1982 (Box B52)
  - Itmann Odd Jobs, vols. 2-9, 1979-1984 (Box B53)
  - Itmann Outside, vols. 3000-3005, 3007-3009, 1977-1986 (Box B53)
  - Itmann Outside, vols. 3000-3009, 1977-1986 (Box B53)
  - Upper & Lower Split - Horsepen Seam, 1975-1979 (Box B53)
  - Amonate, 1963, 1974, 1979 (Box B53)
  - Bishop, 1970, 1980 (Box B53)
  - Pais Coal, 1969 (Box B53)
  - Miscellaneous volumes, 1947-1981 (Box B53)
    (14 vols.)
  - Turkey Gap, 1934-1979 (Box B54)
    (57 vols.)
  - Turkey Gap, 1936-1982 (Box B55)
  - Buchanan County Mine No. 20, vols. 1, 3, 5, 1959 (Box B55)
  - Bishop, 1967-1970 (Box B55)
  - Buchanan Coal Field, 1959 (Box B55)
  - Pocahontas Corporation Leaseline, 1947 (Box B55)
  - Itmann Prospecting, 1961 (Box B55)
  - Assorted volumes, 1946-1980 (Box B55)
  - Faraday, 1944-1948, 1953, 1978 (Box B55)
  - Pocahontas Loc., vols. 7701, 7708, 1952, 1958 (Box B55)
  - Bandy, 1968, 1981 (Box B55)
  - Pigeon Branch, 1970-1978 (Box B55)
  - Beech Fork, 1974-1977 (Box B55)
  - H and D No. 9 Seam, 1975-1976 (Box B55)
  - Upper and Lower Split – Horsepen Seam, 1973-1980 (Box B55)
  - Amonate, 1961, 1972 (Box B55)
  - Nassau, 1964-1965 (Box B55)
  - Turkey Gap, 1968-1975 (Box B56)
  - Miscellaneous, 1968-1982 (Box B56)
  - Amonate, 1957-1979 (Box B56)
  - Sewell Seam, 1963-1966 (Box B56)
  - Rowland, 1964 (Box B56)
  - Lillybrook, 1961-1968 (Box B56)
  - Kepler, 1970 (Box B56)
  - Still Run, 1966 (Box B56)
  - Crane Creek, 1963-1971 (Box B56)
  - Miscellaneous, 1954-1974 (Box B56)
  - [Land tracts?], vols. 9018, 9021-9023, 9025, 1948-1953 (Box B57)
  - Assorted, 1963-1978 (Box B57)
  - Accident book, 1955 (Box B57)
  - Assorted (including Delta, Rolfe No. 3 Seam, Shamokin Stripping, Jenkin Jones Stripping, South Fork), 1942-1960 (Box B57)
  - Unidentified, 1945-1973, undated (Box B57)
    (23 vols.)
  - Amonate, 1958-1973 (Box B58)
  - Buchanan Co., 1959-1960 (Box B58)
  - Itmann, 1946 (Box B58)
  - Matthews, 1984-1985 (Box B58)
  - No. 31 Check Survey, 1936-1958 (Box B58)
  - Assorted, including Bishop, Beckley Seam, No. 3-5 Seams, Laurel Creek, Amonate, Itmann, 1934-1983 (Box B58)
  - Pocahontas, 1942-1955 (Box B58)
  - Kepler, 1968-1973 (Box B59)
  - No. 38 Mine, 1950 (Box B59)
  - Contracted Jobs, Nassau, Nassau Strip, West Virginia, Bandy Strip, Virginia, 1967-1977 (Box B59)
  - JenkinJones Land Tracts, 1958-1972 (Box B59)
  - Smith Seam Upper Split, Laurel Creek No. 2, 1958-1976 (Box B59)
  - Delta, Angle and Norfolk Lick Branch, Caswell Creek No. 6 Seam, 1950-1969 (Box B59)
  - Arista Tonnage, 1961-1968 (Box B59)
  - Crane Creek No. 9 and No. 12 Mines, 1983-1984 (Box B59)
  - Horsepen Blast Hole Drill Logs, 2 vols., 1976-1977 (Box B59)
  - Coalbank Strip Blast Hole Drill Logs, 1976-1978 (Box B59)
  - Pocahontas, 1951-1966 (Box B60)
  - Assorted, 1942-1960 (Box B60)
  - State of Tennessee, Department of Conservation, Division of Geology, assorted bulletins, 1921-1965 (Box B61)
  - Tennessee Division of Geology bulletins, 1956 (Box B61)
  - Soil surveys, Claiborne County, Tennessee, 1939 (Box B61)
  - Geology and Mineral Resources of Wise County and the Coal-Bearing Portion of Scott County, VA, 1923 (Box B61)
  - Natural Resource Management Plan, Cumberland Gap National Historical Park, 1978/08 (Box B61)
  - Geologic Features of Cumberland Gap Area, 1961 (Box B61)
  - Annotated Bibliography of the Geology of Tennessee, 1970/01 (Box B61)
  - Forest Statistics for Tennessee Counties and East Tennessee Counties, 1989 (Box B61)
  - Distribution Maps for Midsouth for Midsouth Tree Species, 1990/04 (Box B61)
  - 1988-1989 Roster of Licensed Contractors, State of Tennessee, 1988-1989 (Box B61)
  - Cumberland Gap, National Historical Park / KY-TN-VA, master plan, 1979/05 (Box B61)
  - Cumberland Gap, National Historical Park / KY-TN-VA, final environmental statement, 1978/10 (Box B61)
  - New Publications of the U.S. Geological Survey, 1990/11 (Box B61)
  - Geological Society of Kentucky Field Trip, 1961 (Box B61)
  - Water-Data Coordination, 1979/04 (Box B61)
  - Catalog of Information on Water Data (Ohio and Tennessee), 1974 (Box B61)
  - Catalog of Southeast US Earthquakes, 1754 through, 1975 (Box B61)
  - Bureau of Mines, Reports of Investigations, Estimate of Known Recoverable Reserves and Preparation and Carbonizing Properties of Coking Coal, numerous counties in Tennessee, 1955-1956 (Box B61)
  - Index to Water Data Activities in Coal Provinces of US, 1979 (Box B61)
  - Availability of Ground Water, Department of Interior, 1962 (Box B62)
  - Geologic Quadrangle Maps of US, Dept of Interior, 1975, 1978 (Box B62)
  - Geologic Map of Tennessee, 1966 (Box B62)
  - Coal and Coke Manual, Norfolk and Western Railway, 1965 (Box B62)
  - Report re: Undeveloped Pocahontas Property, 1931-1934 (Box B62)
  - Survey of Coal Reserves on Southern Railway System, 1964 (Box B62)
  - Virginia Press Association, 1928 (Box B62)
  - Letter from US Dept. Of the Interior, Geological Survey to Consolidated Coal Company, with data sheets and topographical maps for the Tackett Creek basin, Claiborne County, Tennessee, 1980 (Box B62)
  - General Report of the Parrott Mine of the Pulaski-Anthracite Coal Company, Parrott, Virginia, 1924 (Box B62)
  - Coal Mines on the Chesapeake and Ohio Railway, 1966 (Box B62)
- Series IV. Ledgers, 1916-1993, 45.02 Cubic Feet; 42 boxes
  Series IV. Ledgers, 1916-1993, contains 42 boxes, totaling 45.02 cu. ft. It primarily consists of survey record books (not field notebooks). Many record "Survey By", "Traverse by", Notebook No., Page No., Station, Azimuth, Reduced Vernier, Cosine, Horizontal Distances, Sine, Latitude (North and South), Departure (East and West), Sums of Latitude (N&S) and of Departure (E&W), Remarks. N.B.: TT looks like pi sometimes.
  - Survey ledger for Pocahontas Fuel Co., Inc., Ritter Leasehold, Wyoming County, West Virginia (Box L01)
  - Trimore survey ledger, Pocahontas Fuel Co., Inc. and Block Coal and Coke Co., Indian Creek (Box L01)
  - Pocahontas-Boissevain Outside survey ledger, Pocahontas Fuel Co., Inc. and Pocahontas Consolidated Collieries Company, Limited, ca. 1930s-1950s (Box L02)
  - Pocahontas Big Vein Boissevain survey ledger, Pocahontas Fuel Co., Inc., house lots, Pocahontas town lots, ca. 1950s-1970s (Box L03)
  - TT 21 JJ Outside, JenkinJones, Boissevain survey ledger, Pocahontas Fuel Co., Inc., Pocahontas Consolidated Collieries Company, Inc. (Box L04)
  - Turkey Gap Mine Coordinates, Wenonah No. 1, Inactive ledger, Turkey Gap Coal & Coke Co. Engineering Department, Wenonah Mine Traverse, 1918-ca. 1920s (Box L04)
  - Survey ledger for Sagamore No. 6 Seam, Sagamore No. 11 Seam, Crane Creek No. 6 and 11, Pocahontas Fuel Co., Inc., Pocahontas Consolidated Collieries Company, Inc. (Box L05)
  - TT 31 Itmann Outside survey ledger, Pocahontas Consolidated Collieries Company, Inc. (Box L05)
  - TT 45 Itmann Outside survey ledger, Pocahontas Fuel Co., Inc., Pocahontas Consolidated Collieries Company, Inc., Itmann No. 3B Mine, Itmann No. 3 Mine, Itmann No. 4 Mine, includes traverse program print outs and map (Box L06)
  - TT 2 survey ledger, Pocahontas Fuel Co., Inc. and Pocahontas Consolidated Collieries Company, Inc., ca. 1950s (Box L07)
  - Continued from TT 21, JenkinJones survey ledger, Pocahontas Consolidated Collieries Company and Pocahontas Fuel Co., Inc., 1974, undated (Box L07)
  - No. 37 Mine, No. 38 Mine survey ledger, Pocahontas Fuel Co., Inc., Inc. (Box L08)
  - Rolfe Location, Cherokee and Caswell Creek, Sagamore survey ledger (Box L08)
  - Itmann, Lynco, Buckeye survey ledger, Pocahontas Fuel Co., Inc., ca. 1970s (Box L09)
  - Rolfe survey ledger, Pocahontas Fuel Co., Inc., Pocahontas Consolidated Collieries, Inc., Norfolk Coal and Coke Company, ca. 1970s, undated (Box L09)
  - TT-1, Ritter, Kepler survey ledger, Pocahontas Fuel Co., Inc. (Box L10)
  - Bigvein survey ledger, Pocahontas Consolidated Collieries Inc. (Box L11)
  - Boissevain survey pages, Pocahontas Consolidated Collieries Inc. (Box L11)
  - Assorted ledger sheets, Pocahontas Consolidated Collieries Inc. (Box L11)
  - No. 31, No. 3 Seam, Crane Creek No. 6 and No. 11 survey ledger, Pocahontas Fuel Co., Inc., ca. 1950s-1970s (Box L11)
  - Amonate - Bishop Lots and Tracts survey ledger, Pocahontas Fuel Co., Inc. (Box L12)
  - Boissevain survey ledger, Pocahontas Fuel Co., Inc., Pocahontas Consolidated Collieries Inc., ca. 1930s-1970s (Box L12)
  - JJ 5 survey ledger, JenkinJones No. 5, No. 3 Seam, Pocahontas Consolidated Collieries Inc., Pocahontas Fuel Co., Inc. (Box L13)
  - No. 34 Check Survey ledger, Pocahontas Fuel Co., Inc., Pocahontas Consolidated Collieries Inc., ca. 1930s-1940s (Box L14)
  - Lick Branch-Maybeury, Angle, Property Survey T.T.-1 survey ledger, Pocahontas Fuel Co., Inc., 1953, undated (Box L14)
  - Itmann Lots survey ledger, Pocahontas Fuel Co., Inc., with loose printouts (Box L15)
  - No. 33 Mine survey ledger, Pocahontas Fuel Co., Inc., Pocahontas Consolidated Collieries Inc., Bishop (Box L15)
  - Lease Lines survey ledger, Sagamore, Norfolk, Rolfe, Angle, Delta, etc., Pocahontas Fuel Co., Inc., Pocahontas Consolidated Collieries Inc. (Box L16)
  - Gross Tons Shipped Report to Pocahontas Land Corporation, Vol. No. 7, 1950 (Box L16)
  - Guyandotte Still Run Outside survey ledger, Itmann No. 3 Mine, 1961 (Box L17)
  - 3 Sagamore survey ledger, Crane Creek No. 6 Seam, 1961 (Box L17)
  - 50 Pinnacle lots survey ledger (Box L17)
  - The Weyanoke Coal & Coke Co. survey ledger, 1952, undated (Box L17)
  - S. J. Patterson Pocahontas Co., Record of Surveys, No. 1 Mine, No. 3 Mine (Box L18)
  - The Weyanoke Coal and Coke Co., Record of Surveys, Old Weyanoke and No. 3 Mine, Arista (Box L18)
  - Survey ledger for Rowland Coal Company, Division of Consolidation Coal Company, Inc., Itmann No. 3 Mine and other locations, Check surveys/tabulations of traverse, 1979-1986, undated (Box L19)
  - Engineering Department Traverse ledger, Heanagar Mine, Lego Lease, Hugh Branch, Midget Coal Company, No. 1 Mine (Box L19)
  - Mine Coordinates, Turkey Gap, Inactive, Turkey Gap Coal and Coke Company (Box L20)
  - Employee payroll ledger, unidentified company and Crozer Coal and Land Company - Turkey Gap Operation, Dott, West Virginia, 1962-1963 (Box L21)
    RESTRICTED ACCESS: Social Security Numbers
  - Consolidation Coal Company, Tennessee Division, Matthews Mine, outside surveys ledger, 1966-1990 (Box L22)
  - Consolidation Coal Company, Tennessee Division, Inside Surveys, Morco Mines ledger, ca. 1960s (Box L22)
  - Consolidation Coal Company, Matthews Mine, Inside Surveys, No. 1 North Mains, Volume 2 ledger, 1978-1990 (Box L23)
  - Engineering Department, Louisville Coal & Coke Company, Goodville, West Virginia ledger (Box L24)
  - Consolidation Coal Company, Matthews Mine, Inside Survey, No. 3 North Mains Volume 2 ledger, 1977-1990 (Box L25)
  - Turkey Gap, punch and strip, ledger, Crozer Coal and Land Company - Turkey Gap Operation (Box L26)
  - Vol. No. 1, Outside Surveys Traverse Book ledger (assorted tracts of land) (Box L27)
  - Deerfield Traverse Sheets, American Coal Company of Allegany County Engineering Department (Box L28)
  - Virginian Lear No. 1 Inside Traverse Sheets, Mine No. 151, Old Sheets, The Consolidation Coal Company, Engineering Department, 1972, undated (Box L29)
  - Consolidation Coal Company, Tennessee Division, Matthews Mines, Inside Surveys, No. 2 North Mains, Vol. 1 ledger, 1968-1989 (Box L30)
  - Consolidation Coal Company, Tennessee Division, Matthews Mines, Insider Surveys, No. 1 North Mains, Vol. 1 ledger, 1968-1978, undated (Box L31)
  - Consolidation Coal Company, Tennessee Division, Matthews Mines, Inside Surveys, No. 3 North Mains, Vol. 1 ledger, 1970-1977, undated (Box L32)
  - Guyandotte, Still Run, Inside, TT 32, Itmann, Cabin Creek, No. 3 Mine, No. 2 Mine, 1959-1961 (Box L33)
  - 66 Covel ledger, 5 JenkinJones Lots sheets, 78 Faraday Lands sheets, 8 Bishop Lots sheets (all found within 66 Covel ledger) (Box L33)
  - 40 Piedmont ledger (Box L33)
  - Crane Creek No. 9-No. 12 ledger, Southern Appalachia Region, 1982-1984 (Box L34)
  - 78 Faraday Lands ledger (Box L34)
  - 87 Ritter ledger (Box L34)
  - Deerfield Daily Cost Report, 1957-1960 (Box L35)
  - Itmann Daily Cost Report, 1957-1960 (Box L35)
  - Bishop No. 35 and No. 36 Mines ledger, Southern Appalachia Region, 1978-1982 (Box L35)
  - JenkinJones - Boissevain, JenkinJones No. 5 Mine, No. 3 Seam, Pocahontas Land Corporation lands ledger - columns for square feet, Acres, Section, Net Tonnage, "N. P. Sq. Ft.", and "AC." for pillars, headings, and rooms in Virginia and West Virginia, 1958-1983 (Box L36)
  - JenkinJones No. 5 Mine, columns for square feet, section, cubic feet, tonnage, and "N.P. Sq. Ft." for headings, rooms, and sections, by person and month, 1952-1956 (Box L36)
  - JenkinJones No. 5 Mine, No. 7 Colliery, Pocahontas Land Coporation, columns for square feet, section, cubic feet, tonnage, and "N.P. Sq. Ft." for headings, rooms, and sections, by person and month, 1950-1952 (Box L36)
  - South Fork, 1950-1951, JenkinJones No. 4 Seam, Ballard-Harman Branch, 1976-1986, columns for square feet, section, cubic feet, tonnage, "N.P. Sq. Ft.", "N.P. Acres", and abandoned acres, square feet, and tons for headings, rooms, and sections, by person and month, Pocahontas Land Corporation, 1950-1951, 1976-1986 (Box L36)
  - Amonate No. 31 Mine, No. 4 Seam, quarterly reports for acres, average height, net tons, for headings and rooms, 1977-1993 (Box L36)
  - Report on the Smokeless Coal Fields of Greenbrier and Nicholas Counties, 1923 (Box L36)
  - Killarney ledger, Killarney Smokeless Coal Company, Inc., Engineering Department, Killarney-Beckley Seam, No. 1 Mine, Crozer Land Association, undated (Box L37)
  - Modoc and Wenonah Outside Turkey Gap ledger, ca. 1920s (Box L38)
  - Itmann No. 6 Mine ledger, 1961, undated (Box L39)
  - Amonate No. 7 Mine, Mine Work ledger, undated (Box L39)
  - 8, Turkey Gap Coal and Coke Company ledger, Turkey Gap No. 9 Seam, Crozer Land Association, Outcrop No. 11 Seam, undated (Box L39)
  - Turkey Gap ledger, Southern Appalachia Region, 1979-1982 (Box L39)
  - Tennessee Coal, Iron, and Railroad Company, Report on Raw Materials, Report No. SD-1939-6, Birmingham, Alabama, 1939/08 (Box L40)
  - W. M. Ritter Lumber Company, Columbus, Ohio, Engineering Department, Big Vein Pocahontas Property, Buchanan County, Virginia, survey ledger, 1928-1951 (Box L41)
  - No. 3 Seam Outcrop Traverse, Turkey Gap, Pocahontas Coal and Coke Company, Turkey Gap Coal and Coke Company, stations and coordinates, 1916-1958 (Box L41)
  - Typical Analyses, Bituminous Coals, Produced in Districts 7 and 8, Data Book Volume 1, 1941 (Box L41)
  - Mine No. 151 - Mains, The Consolidation Coal Company, Engineering Department, survey ledger, undated (Box L42)
  - Mine No. 154, Traverse Sheets, New North Side, survey ledger, Consolidation Coal Company, undated (Box L42)
  - North Main, Virginian Lear [?], Inside Old Traverse Sheets, Consolidation Coal Company, undated (Box L42)